<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-16T15:55:55-08:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Daily Update</title><link href="/simply%20scheme/python/code:%20the%20hidden%20language%20of%20computers/2020/11/14/Daily-Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Update" /><published>2020-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/simply%20scheme/python/code:%20the%20hidden%20language%20of%20computers/2020/11/14/Daily-Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/simply%20scheme/python/code:%20the%20hidden%20language%20of%20computers/2020/11/14/Daily-Update.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finished Chapter 18 exercises from &lt;em&gt;Simply Scheme&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spent a lot more time on Course Project for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/galaxy-project/home/welcome&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Genomic Data Science
with
Galaxy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
I am not so sure that this course is worth the time that I am putting
into it. While Galaxy seems like a good tool for doing genomic
analysis and it does provide good examples of reproducible workflows,
I really only was doing the course as a part of the certification. I
may end up finishing it when I have actually completed the other
course in the specialization.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reading:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Chapter 12: Binary Adding Machine from &lt;em&gt;Code: The Hidden Language of Computers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="simply scheme" /><category term="python" /><category term="Code: The Hidden Language of Computers" /><summary type="html">Finished Chapter 18 exercises from Simply Scheme.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily_update</title><link href="/simply%20scheme/genomics/2020/11/13/Daily_Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily_update" /><published>2020-11-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/simply%20scheme/genomics/2020/11/13/Daily_Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/simply%20scheme/genomics/2020/11/13/Daily_Update.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Worked on the Course Project for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/galaxy-project/home/welcome&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Genomic Data Science with Galaxy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finished 18.5! I ended up re-writing my lateral function to do the
passing over instead of my depth-wise function, which allowed me to
eliminate the blank lists that I had kept ending up with before.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="simply scheme" /><category term="genomics" /><summary type="html">Worked on the Course Project for Genomic Data Science with Galaxy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Update</title><link href="/genomics/simply%20scheme/2020/11/12/Daily-Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Update" /><published>2020-11-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/genomics/simply%20scheme/2020/11/12/Daily-Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/genomics/simply%20scheme/2020/11/12/Daily-Update.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Module 4 and 5 of &lt;em&gt;Genomic Data Science with Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; course.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spent lots of time working on 18.5 of &lt;em&gt;Simply Scheme&lt;/em&gt;. I think that
the way that I am trying to pass over the parts of the list that I
don’t want to keep is the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="genomics" /><category term="simply scheme" /><summary type="html">Module 4 and 5 of Genomic Data Science with Galaxy course.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Update</title><link href="/bioinformatics/website/jekyll/2020/11/10/Daily-Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Update" /><published>2020-11-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/bioinformatics/website/jekyll/2020/11/10/Daily-Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bioinformatics/website/jekyll/2020/11/10/Daily-Update.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Completed the &lt;em&gt;Johns Hopkins University: Introduction to Genomic
Technologies&lt;/em&gt; on Coursera.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Worked on cleaning up the navigation on my website.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="bioinformatics" /><category term="website" /><category term="jekyll" /><summary type="html">Completed the Johns Hopkins University: Introduction to Genomic Technologies on Coursera.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Update</title><link href="/coding/update/2020/11/09/Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Update" /><published>2020-11-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/coding/update/2020/11/09/Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/coding/update/2020/11/09/Update.html">&lt;p&gt;The last couple of weeks have been hectic, both nationally and
personally. I probably have let the national get too much in the way of
personal. I have been getting more studying done, but have been
prioritizing it over writing up what I am doing. This is not
the most positive, as I do tend to stay on track better when documenting
what I am working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the things that I had been doing before, I also have been
going over my resume and have started applying for jobs. This has become
a bit more of a realistic possibility as Gio has started attending a
“SAFE” learning center offered by the school district.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been focusing more on the coding side of things than
studying for the CCNA as that is the direction that I would like
to head, though I certainly am continuing to study for it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="coding" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">The last couple of weeks have been hectic, both nationally and personally. I probably have let the national get too much in the way of personal. I have been getting more studying done, but have been prioritizing it over writing up what I am doing. This is not the most positive, as I do tend to stay on track better when documenting what I am working on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Progress</title><link href="/2020/10/29/Daily-Progress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Progress" /><published>2020-10-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-10-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/2020/10/29/Daily-Progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/10/29/Daily-Progress.html">&lt;p&gt;This week has been quite hectic, with a lot of it taken up continuing
to winterize our trailer, helping random friends with things, and school
for my son. The good news is that my son has gotten into one of the
school districts SAFE learning centers and so I should have more time to
focus on studying and applying for more jobs. I also have been working
on my resume, signing up for job fairs, and other job hunt related
things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finished through exercise 17.6 in &lt;em&gt;Simply Scheme&lt;/em&gt;. So far, this
chapter has somehow felt more “real”, yet not to hard.&lt;br /&gt;
  17.6 however asked you to implement a function that produced the
  same result as the standard &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;append&lt;/code&gt; scheme primitive, only using
  the list primitives &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cons&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;car&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cdr&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
  The whole thing seemed pretty straight forward, until I spent over 2
  days on this working trying to get it so that not only would it
  return a list of the same elements as the regular &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;append&lt;/code&gt; function
  but so that it would do it in the correct order.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I still don’t think my solution is as elegant or simplified as it
  could be, but it does function correctly. And while it doesn’t
  probably matter that it is optimized, as there is already a function
  for doing this, I think optimizing it would be helpful for my
  further understanding of using lists and help me think more deeply
  about the problem. Plus being satisfying…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read through pg 46 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Python-Data-Analysis-Wrangling-IPython/dp/1449319793&quot;&gt;Python for Data Analysis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This week has been quite hectic, with a lot of it taken up continuing to winterize our trailer, helping random friends with things, and school for my son. The good news is that my son has gotten into one of the school districts SAFE learning centers and so I should have more time to focus on studying and applying for more jobs. I also have been working on my resume, signing up for job fairs, and other job hunt related things.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Progress</title><link href="/simply%20schme/rv/winterizing/2020/10/25/Daily-Progress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Progress" /><published>2020-10-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-10-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/simply%20schme/rv/winterizing/2020/10/25/Daily-Progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="/simply%20schme/rv/winterizing/2020/10/25/Daily-Progress.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Exercises through 17.4 of &lt;em&gt;Simply Scheme&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spent a good chunk of the morning looking for jobs and working on my resume.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The afternoon was spent getting our trailer ready for winter, with the
first night below 20°f. We are trying a skirt made from a
non-woven house wrap this year. I also covered some of our windows
with clear film. The taping for these was tedious, but putting the
film on and shrinking it is very satisfying. The windows covered with
this film feel much warmer than the other ones.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="simply schme" /><category term="RV" /><category term="winterizing" /><summary type="html">Exercises through 17.4 of Simply Scheme.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Progress</title><link href="/ccna/simply%20schme/2020/10/24/Daily-Progress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Progress" /><published>2020-10-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-10-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/ccna/simply%20schme/2020/10/24/Daily-Progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ccna/simply%20schme/2020/10/24/Daily-Progress.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read &lt;strong&gt;Part V&lt;/strong&gt; introduction and started on &lt;strong&gt;Chapter 17&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Simply
Scheme&lt;/em&gt;. I was really excited about starting this part because it
actually feels like the book is diving into programming and not simply
providing a gentler introduction to it. Which is no criticism of the
gentle introduction, I feel very well prepared going into this
section, but this feels much more substantial and applicative to the
“real world” than previous sections have felt.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Continued making the review Anki flashcards for chapter 2 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3dHP3P0&quot;&gt;Wendell Odom’s CCNA  guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ccna" /><category term="simply schme" /><summary type="html">Read Part V introduction and started on Chapter 17 of Simply Scheme. I was really excited about starting this part because it actually feels like the book is diving into programming and not simply providing a gentler introduction to it. Which is no criticism of the gentle introduction, I feel very well prepared going into this section, but this feels much more substantial and applicative to the “real world” than previous sections have felt.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Progress</title><link href="/ccna/simply%20schme/2020/10/23/Daily-Progress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Progress" /><published>2020-10-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-10-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/ccna/simply%20schme/2020/10/23/Daily-Progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ccna/simply%20schme/2020/10/23/Daily-Progress.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finished the remaining exercises in Chapter 16 of &lt;em&gt;Simply Scheme&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Started on making the review Anki flashcards for chapter 2 fo &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3dHP3P0&quot;&gt;Wendell Odom’s CCNA  guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ccna" /><category term="simply schme" /><summary type="html">Finished the remaining exercises in Chapter 16 of Simply Scheme.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Update</title><link href="/simply%20scheme/ccna/python/jekyll/website/2020/10/21/Daily-Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Update" /><published>2020-10-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-10-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/simply%20scheme/ccna/python/jekyll/website/2020/10/21/Daily-Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/simply%20scheme/ccna/python/jekyll/website/2020/10/21/Daily-Update.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The big thing was finishing exercise 16.20. This exercise felt quite
challenging, as it required understanding exactly how a function that
someone else wrote, and then expanding it using a function that was
similar required different inputs and a different set of recursions. I
may work on a write-up or video of it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read Chapter 2 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3dHP3P0&quot;&gt;Wendell Odom’s CCNA
guide&lt;/a&gt;. While the video courses feel a bit
easier and are maybe less “dry”(a common critique of Odom’s book), for
me anyways they are much harder to retain information or study from.
This book in particular is divided into chunks that are a great size
for studying. This makes sense as they are written with studying in
mind and have a section at the beginning that tells you exactly how
they are meant to be used.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The reading sections of each chapter consist of around 1 - 1.5 hours
worth of material, and they have very clear review sections at the end
of each chapter. There are also other “review” subdivisions that I
will discuss when I get to them.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;My plan up to this point has been to read the chapter on one day and
then create Anki flash cards on the next day using the review section
as a guide. I will detail this process more later. As an aid to the
creation of flash cards, I also purchased the Premium Digital Edition
of the book directly through Pearson. The print version of the book
includes an excellent coupon for this that makes it very affordable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finished re-reading the basic &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/step-by-step/01-setup/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jekyll Step-by-Step Tutorial&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="simply scheme" /><category term="ccna" /><category term="python" /><category term="jekyll" /><category term="website" /><summary type="html">The big thing was finishing exercise 16.20. This exercise felt quite challenging, as it required understanding exactly how a function that someone else wrote, and then expanding it using a function that was similar required different inputs and a different set of recursions. I may work on a write-up or video of it.</summary></entry></feed>